New York State Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training Records 5383
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training Records
1946-1954
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training
5383
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Training Manuals designed to help teachers of industrial education in the secondary schools, NYS
5622226
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 15, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
At the conclusion of World War II, the Curriculum Laboratory which had been set up at Cornell to develop training material for the war industries was transferred to the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, and continued to develop training manuals. These manuals were designed to help the teachers of industrial education in the secondary schools throughout the State.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Vocational education -- New York (State) -- Handbooks, manuals, etc; United States. Bureau of Labor Statistics; New York (State) Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
5622226
- Applied Biology, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Applied Biology, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training. August. Item is in English.
- Applied Chemistry, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Applied Chemistry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bacteriology for Nurses, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Bacteriology for Nurses, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    By Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training. June. Item is in English.
- Dental Mechanics, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Full Denture Construction, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Electrical Apprentice IV, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Related Information Electrical Apprentice IV, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    By Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training. January. Item is in English.
- English for Vocational Schools, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: English for Vocational Schools`, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    By Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training. April. Item is in English.
- Farming Programs, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Supervised Farming Programs in Vocational Education, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Food Trades, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Related Science Food Trades, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 2: Food Trades Occupations, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Homemaking Education, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Planning Guide Homemaking Education, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    By Bureau of Home Economics Education. July. Item is in English.
- Junior Aviation Aerodynamics, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Junior Aviation Aerodynamics Theory of Flight, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    By Bureau of Industrial and Technical Education. January. Item is in English.
- Junior Aviation Meteorology, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Junior Aviation Meteorology, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    By Bureau of Industrial and Technical Education. Item is in English.
- Machine Shop Practice, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Suggested Related Instruction in Design, Materials and Manufacturing for Apprenctices in Machine Shop Practice, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Machine Trades, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Related Science Machine Trades, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Machinist Apprentice II, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Machinist Apprentice II, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    By Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training. July. Item is in English.
- Machinist Apprentice III, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Machinist Apprentice III, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    By Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training. Item is in English.
- Machinist Apprentice IV, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Machinist Apprentice IV, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Machinist Apprentice Answer Book, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Machinist Apprentice Answer Book, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    By Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher TrainingBureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training. For courses I, II, III, and IV. Item is in English.
- Printing Trades, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Printing Presswork Related Instruction, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 2: Printing Trades Occupations, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Related Information: Ceramic Area, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Suggested Related Information for the Ceramics Area, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Related Information: Electricity Area, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Suggested Related Information for the Electricity Area, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Related Information: Printing Area, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Printing Area Industrial Arts Related Information, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    By Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training. February. Item is in English.
- Related Information: Textile Area, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Suggested Related Information for the Textiles Area, Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Related Information: Wood Area, 1950; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Suggested Related Information for the Wood Area, Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Sanitary Food Handling, 1954; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: Sanitary Food Handling, Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Watch Clock Making, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: Watch and Clock Making Suggested Related Information, Publication (Box 1, Folder 25)
    By Bureau of Vocational Curriculum Development and Industrial Teacher Training. March. Item is in English.